ERIC QUELCH

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

519-802-2824 quelchx@gmail.com London, Ontario http://quelchx.com http://github.com/quelchx

EDUCATION

Information Systems and Web Development Fanshawe College Sept 2020 - April 2022 London, Ontario 3.7 GPA

Undergraduate Computer Science Mohawk College February 2019 - May 2020 Hamilton, Ontario

PROFILE

A talented IT professional with a passion for tailored solutions seeking a position as a Web Developer in a thriving, exciting and growing company. Comes with a college degree in Information Systems and almost 4 years of experience with HTML, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, NextJS and the fundamentals of Django and NodeJS. Able to provide quality support to the company's IT team in developing and deploying web-based event and registration software tools.

DEVELOPER SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Javascript, TypeScript, Python, PHP, C#, SQL

FRAMEWORKS AND LIBRARIES

- · React, NextJS, VueJS, NuxtJS, NodeJS, Express, Django, Ruby on Rails
- Firebase, MongoDB, Postgres, MySQL
- · Mongoose, Typeorm, Prisma
- Wordpress, Strapi CMS, Nuxt Content, VuePress
- ThreeJS, React Framer Motion, React Spring, AOS, GSAP
- TailwindCSS, Bulma, Bootstrap, Materialize, SASS

SOFTWARE AND SERVICES

- · Netlify, Vercel, Firebase, Heroku
- · Azure, AWS, Linode
- Figma, Adobe Photoshop
- · Git, GitHub, Docker, Bitbucket, Atlassian, Jira

EXPERIENCE

TUTOR, FANSHAWE COLLEGE; LONDON, ON -2020 - 2021

- Brainstormed with students in setting realistic academic and career goals.
- · Designed customized materials based on students interest.
- Composed engaging lesson plans, giving students the opportunity to further their understanding of complex material, boosting motivation and session preparation for students.
- Collaborated with students to complete homework assignments, identify lagging skills and assisted with correcting weaknesses.
- Planned sessions and allowed time to strengthen weak subjects and build skills.
- Provided early intervention assistance to struggling students.

TECHNICIAN SUPERVISOR, KAL TIRE; LONDON, ON -2019 - 2021

• Managed, trained and supervised a team of 5 to 8 junior technicians.

- Performed inspections of all vehicle types within MTO guidelines.
- Diagnosed issues and performed proper tasks to fix occurring problems.
- Maintained fleet vehicles in good working order accordance with OEM preventive and corrective maintenance schedules.
- Serviced tires, repaired tire injuries within specific guidelines, changed or topped off fluids and completed various maintenance when required.

CERTIFICATIONS

Ontario Smart Serve — Alcohol and Gaming Commission, August 15, 2018
C# Unity Developer 2D Course — Udemy, March 28, 2020
C# Unity Developer 3D Course — Udemy, April 4, 2020
Web Developer Bootcamp Course — Udemy, May 23, 2020
Modern React with Redux Course — Udemy, June 5, 2020
Complete VueJS (Vuex, Vue-Router) Course — Udemy, September 8, 2020
React, NodeJS, Express & MongoDB Course — Udemy, October 22, 2020
NuxtJS - VueJS on Steroids Course — Udemy, November 1, 2020
VueJS & Firebase Course — Udemy, November 9, 2020

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Vue Writer - Creator — http://npmjs.com/package/vue-writer AOS Vue - Creator — http://npmjs.com/package/aos-vue HFX CSS - Creator — http://npmjs.com/package/hfx-css

REFERENCES

Jim Cooper - Professor — Fanshawe College

jcooper@fanshaweonline.ca

Marcelo Espanhol - Professor — Fanshawe College

m_hespanhol@fanshaweonline.ca

Martin Cserhati - Program Coordinator, Professor — Fanshawe College

- mcserhati@fanshawec.ca
- 519-670-7178